<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Derek Zoladz</title>
    <link>https://www.derekzoladz.com/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://www.derekzoladz.com/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2023 Derek C. Zoladz</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://www.derekzoladz.com/media/icon_hu1efd8f6f495040e8e1031572b668117b_2834_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.derekzoladz.com/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speculative Library Futures</title>
      <link>https://www.derekzoladz.com/project/tedsig_futures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.derekzoladz.com/project/tedsig_futures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Speculative Library Futures | Post-Pandemic Libraries&lt;/strong&gt; is the culmination of a yearlong exploration of speculative design and libraries by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.alaoweb.org/igs/tedsig/index.html/&#34;&gt;TEDSIG&lt;/a&gt;, the Technical, Electronic, and Digital Services Interest Group of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.alaoweb.org/&#34;&gt;Academic Library Association of Ohio&lt;/a&gt;.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Publication: &lt;a href=&#34;https://futures.alaoweb.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Speculative Library Futures | Post-Pandemic Libraries&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;doi: &lt;a href=&#34;http://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.4606860&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.4606860&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;!-- Article Teasers --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://futures.alaoweb.org/speculative-deck.html/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Speculative Card Deck&lt;/a&gt; by Mackenzie Salisbury and Shannon Marie Robinson integrates Guy Debord&amp;rsquo;s dérive into a beautifully-designed, critical deck of prompts and actions to generate situations that disrupt the traditional use value assigned to the library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://futures.alaoweb.org/notes-on-a-speculative-design-reading-group.html/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Notes on a Speculative Design Reading Group&lt;/a&gt; by John Jung reflects on the conversations with artists, designers, and librarians that emerged during “Design After the End of the World”, a speculative design reading group at Chicago’s community lab LATITUDE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://futures.alaoweb.org/hair-catalog.html/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Hair Catalog&lt;/a&gt; by Shannon Marie Robinson applies metadata of forensic examination to describe an object, highlighting how traditional metadata, such as title and author, influence discovery and control the development of new knowledges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://futures.alaoweb.org/alternative-art-history.html/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Alternative Art History&lt;/a&gt; by Shannon Marie Robinson reconfigures the relations between archival memory, meaning-making, and how we query knowledge, by shifting away from the dominant perspective of the author and towards the preservation of scholarly communication between readers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://futures.alaoweb.org/tech-to-you.html/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Tech to You&lt;/a&gt; by Myiesha Speight and Bria Sinnott accepts the disintegration of the library as a physical place to explore fundamental questions about the qualifications of librarianship and the definition of impactful public services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://futures.alaoweb.org/growing-through-the-cracks.html/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Growing Through the Cracks&lt;/a&gt; by Heidi Beke-Harrigan and Katie DeJongh asks us to accept stillness as a mode of generative thought, one that encourages optimistic and parallel futures to sprout from a nurturing and reciprocal dialogue between image and haiku.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://futures.alaoweb.org/alexandria.html/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Alexandr.ia&lt;/a&gt; by Calvin Cleary and Liz Lang is a dystopian look at the future of precarity in academic libraries, which takes the form of a satirical pitch to Silicon Valley investors for an app called Alexandr.ia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- Article Teasers --&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The origin of this work finds its roots just off of exit 50, southbound interstate 70, in a rural Holiday Inn. It was a late October afternoon – at an oddly remote conference center in Wilmington, Ohio.  I was listening to a presentation from &lt;a href=&#34;https://johnjung.us/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;John Jung&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://kzadrozny.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Kathy Zadrozny&lt;/a&gt;, both from the University of Chicago, about the use of design fiction – specifically, the creation of believable near-future stories to explore the social, cultural and ethical aspects of technological change. The year was 2016 and this presentation made a deep and lasting impression on me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;img style=&#34;margin-bottom: .5rem;&#34; src=&#34;alao2016_map.png&#34; alt=&#34;open street map aerial view of ohio with an arrow pointing to exit 50&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center; margin-bottom: 2rem; font-size: 14px;&#34;&gt;©2021 OpenStreetMap Contributors | &lt;a href=&#34;https://opendatacommons.org/licenses/odbl/summary/&#34;&gt;ODbL 1.0 license&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast-forward to 2018, when I became co-chair of TEDSIG in July. Taking the interest group in a fresh direction was an intentional decision. Rather than continue to facilitate workshops and schedule learning opportunities that focused on the day-to-day tooling that enables library-specific technical work, I wanted to use this opportunity to reinvigorate our group by reflecting on first principles and foundations. Accepting that many of our existing library systems are reaching the limits of their effectiveness served as a premise to encourage us to consider alternative futures. However, to avoid a future that merely recapitulates both the positive and negative aspects of our present solutions, we needed to think critically about the design of our future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;futures_cone.png&#34; alt=&#34;diagram of the future cones&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://tedsig.alaoweb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;TEDSIG 2020&lt;/a&gt; invited John Jung to present an hour-long exploration of Speculative/Critical Design and Libraries. Speculative design attempts to open our minds to new ways of thinking and being, where traditional design attempts to solve problems. Speculative design holds promise for libraries as a way to problematize our present by exposing the pre-existing conditions of our current reality. Thomas Moynihan: &amp;ldquo;We perceive the world as anticipations of its future&amp;rdquo;. It is our capacity to envision the future that propels us forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We perceive the world as anticipations of its future&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attendees of TEDSIG 2020 were invited to continue the exploration by participating in an 8-week speculative design and climate reading group co-facilitated by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reneelynn.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Renee Albrecht-Mallinger&lt;/a&gt; and John Jung. Beginning in September 2020, &lt;a href=&#34;https://dzoladz.github.io/2020-reading-group/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Design After the End of the World&lt;/a&gt; was hosted by the artist community space &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.latitudechicago.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;LATITUDE | Chicago&lt;/a&gt;. The outcome of this group’s work resulted in the call for proposals for a Speculative Library Futures web-based publication, of which the resulting contributions are included above.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speculative Design &amp; Libraries</title>
      <link>https://www.derekzoladz.com/project/tedsig2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.derekzoladz.com/project/tedsig2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As Co-Chair of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.alaoweb.org/igs/tedsig/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Technical, Electronic, and Digital Services Interest Group&lt;/a&gt; (TEDSIG) - a community within the Academic Library Association of Ohio (ALAO) - my professional experiences have circumvented the shared set of historical struggles that define the group&amp;rsquo;s identity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TEDSIG was founded in 1993 as the Technical Services Interest Group (TSIG). The interest group’s name and scope was changed in June 2007 to Technical, Electronic, and Digital Services Interest Group (TEDSIG) to better reflect the evolving status of the group’s constituents in traditional and emerging technologies. By the time that I began working at Columbus State Community College in 2008, it was evidently clear that the traditional role of technical service librarians was on the decline. As a new professional with a bias towards the use of technology in day-to-day library practices, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t understand why - or how -  the technological aspects of the profession were&amp;hellip; &lt;em&gt;on the way out&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the main co-chair responsibilities is to organize an annual event for members of the TEDSIG community. It&amp;rsquo;s an opportunity to contribute to both the growth, and the future direction, of the group. Pondering the overwhelming emptiness of &amp;lsquo;what to do&amp;rsquo; with this tabla rasa, I explored the confusion of my early experiences of technical work in libraries. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t that technological work in libraries was on the way out, it was that &lt;em&gt;a specific way of conducting that technical work was on the way out&lt;/em&gt;. As I&amp;rsquo;m joining the ranks of the mid-career professionals, this gave me pause. As members of Ohio&amp;rsquo;s TEDSIG community, are we actively designing a future for the next generation of library professionals to step into?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To help us explore the design implications of our current and potential library futures, John Jung was invited to speak at TEDSIG 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;john_jung.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;photo of John Jung&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John Jung is Design Consultant at &lt;a href=&#34;https://johnjung.us/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;johnjung.us&lt;/a&gt; and Programmer/Analyst at The University of Chicago. John is interested in the different ways that research and design might intersect. He has recently spoken on Speculative Design &amp;amp; Strategy at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://johnjung.us/scd_and_strategy.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Symposium on the Future of Libraries&lt;/a&gt; in Seattle, Washington, as well as having lead the provocatively-titled reading group &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.latitudechicago.org/classes-and-workshops/reading-group-design-after-the-end-of-the-world&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Design After the End of the World&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; in his hometown of Chicago. He has a degree in art from Governors State University and a degree in design methods from the IIT Institute of Design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/nv4Frp8p8fw&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speculative and Critical Design and Libraries&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thomas Moynihan once noted: &amp;ldquo;We perceive the world as anticipations of its future&amp;rdquo;. If nothing else, this statement gives us pause. Just enough of a delay to remove us from immediacy. Allowing us to bring our set of expectations and assumptions to the foreground and reflect upon how these projections of a near-term reality guide our decision-making in the present. As many of our existing library systems are reaching the limits of their effectiveness, the struggle is real. To avoid a future that merely recapitulates - both the positive and negative aspects of - our present solutions, we need to think critically about the design of our future. But maybe more so, we need a toolkit to problematize our present. To shake loose our assumptions, and provide just enough distance to consider alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s where Speculative Design is useful. Where traditional design attempts to solve problems, speculative design attempts to open our minds to new ways of thinking and being. If it is our capacity to envision the future that propels us forward, speculative design has promise as a way to allow us to problematize our present, so as not to repeat our past, by exposing the pre-existing conditions of our current reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Augmented Reality at Columbus State Library [Photo Essay]</title>
      <link>https://www.derekzoladz.com/project/thurgood/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.derekzoladz.com/project/thurgood/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thurgood Marshall and the Supreme Court&lt;/em&gt; was an interactive exhibit at the Columbus State Library in 2015. Posters were brought to life using the augmented reality app &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.aurasma.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Aurasma&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Using emerging technology, team members created the exhibit and online guide that was enjoyed and appreciated by the community, ranging from 5th graders to local business leaders. With the help of many collaborators, the team went beyond the exhibit to create a wide range of programs including a film series, an art exhibit, a lecture series, and a companion display and programming in the Bookstore. This innovative and extraordinary program of exhibits and events provided the campus and community with the opportunity to learn more deeply about events and individuals that have had an impact on the way we live today.&amp;rdquo; - &lt;strong&gt;CSCC Quality Team Award, Gold 2016&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;














&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-announcement-board-for-the-exhibit&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;
        &lt;img alt=&#34;Announcement board for the exhibit&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /project/thurgood/exhibit-poster_huf991c7795586ce8e30f1132e1bfa897f_489873_a5140ff14e6686dcb67071808959a9cc.png 400w,
               /project/thurgood/exhibit-poster_huf991c7795586ce8e30f1132e1bfa897f_489873_1f3da7fd66d96872e08bff734f73e569.png 760w,
               /project/thurgood/exhibit-poster_huf991c7795586ce8e30f1132e1bfa897f_489873_1200x1200_fit_lanczos_3.png 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://www.derekzoladz.com/project/thurgood/exhibit-poster_huf991c7795586ce8e30f1132e1bfa897f_489873_a5140ff14e6686dcb67071808959a9cc.png&#34;
               width=&#34;570&#34;
               height=&#34;760&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      Announcement board for the exhibit
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;














&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-post-award-photo-of-the-major-library-staff-contributors-to-the-project&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;
        &lt;img alt=&#34;Post-Award Photo of the Major Library Staff Contributors to the Project.&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /project/thurgood/thurgood-1_hu88438ca17cfc03803f58c65bca1f5290_637185_294a3e8e50f38a1510a79d2bd244e83b.jpg 400w,
               /project/thurgood/thurgood-1_hu88438ca17cfc03803f58c65bca1f5290_637185_52b5ac751c03539f232535d8a8d408f8.jpg 760w,
               /project/thurgood/thurgood-1_hu88438ca17cfc03803f58c65bca1f5290_637185_1200x1200_fit_q75_lanczos.jpg 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://www.derekzoladz.com/project/thurgood/thurgood-1_hu88438ca17cfc03803f58c65bca1f5290_637185_294a3e8e50f38a1510a79d2bd244e83b.jpg&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;592&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      Post-Award Photo of the Major Library Staff Contributors to the Project.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;














&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-view-of-exhibit-from-main-entrance&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;
        &lt;img alt=&#34;View of Exhibit from Main Entrance&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /project/thurgood/thurgood-2_hu67e2d2d21e2d97ebc6a08f2aa166a573_2216387_ef21bd7f38156b4fcd1259f97f5561f7.jpg 400w,
               /project/thurgood/thurgood-2_hu67e2d2d21e2d97ebc6a08f2aa166a573_2216387_5ea2e3394d299ae3e1a42551140a9a6a.jpg 760w,
               /project/thurgood/thurgood-2_hu67e2d2d21e2d97ebc6a08f2aa166a573_2216387_1200x1200_fit_q75_lanczos.jpg 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://www.derekzoladz.com/project/thurgood/thurgood-2_hu67e2d2d21e2d97ebc6a08f2aa166a573_2216387_ef21bd7f38156b4fcd1259f97f5561f7.jpg&#34;
               width=&#34;570&#34;
               height=&#34;760&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      View of Exhibit from Main Entrance
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;














&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-display-at-columbus-state-bookstore&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;
        &lt;img alt=&#34;Display at Columbus State Bookstore&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /project/thurgood/thurgood-3_hu67e2d2d21e2d97ebc6a08f2aa166a573_1521592_de4941ccfc61c44b3428fcb6aebec5a9.jpg 400w,
               /project/thurgood/thurgood-3_hu67e2d2d21e2d97ebc6a08f2aa166a573_1521592_03a85e5467b4c3b1f261f3994353dcb0.jpg 760w,
               /project/thurgood/thurgood-3_hu67e2d2d21e2d97ebc6a08f2aa166a573_1521592_1200x1200_fit_q75_lanczos.jpg 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://www.derekzoladz.com/project/thurgood/thurgood-3_hu67e2d2d21e2d97ebc6a08f2aa166a573_1521592_de4941ccfc61c44b3428fcb6aebec5a9.jpg&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;736&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      Display at Columbus State Bookstore
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s an example of a triggered augmented reality layer for one of the case posters. There is no audio on this clip.

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/hJRJTxkP7tY&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lingo</title>
      <link>https://www.derekzoladz.com/project/lingo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.derekzoladz.com/project/lingo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ohio’s first ILEAD USA was a multi-state immersive continuing education program that develops library leaders through projects based on community needs via the application of participatory technology tools. Ohio participants joined others from Colorado, Illinois, Iowa, and Utah in this national initiative. ILEAD USA was funded by a Laura Bush 21st Century Librarian Program grant to the State Library of Illinois from the Institute of Museum and Library Services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Myself, and a former CSCC colleague Julie Zaveloff, were selected as part of the initial group from Ohio. Our team was rounded out by other librarians from around the state:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kirstin Krumsee, State Library of Ohio&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jessica Crossfield McIntosh, Otterbein University&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;David Green, OhioNet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;














&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-columbus-state-librarians-selected-for-ilead-usa---ohio-2013&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;
        &lt;img alt=&#34;Columbus State Librarians selected for ILEAD USA - OHIO 2013&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /project/lingo/zoladz-zaveloff_hud7eddf99cc6d96d06786be86b4c3694f_43922_ee210508dc147a9ae58669cff05ddc30.jpg 400w,
               /project/lingo/zoladz-zaveloff_hud7eddf99cc6d96d06786be86b4c3694f_43922_e4dbb32cbae0c105f9f24dc11c91ed06.jpg 760w,
               /project/lingo/zoladz-zaveloff_hud7eddf99cc6d96d06786be86b4c3694f_43922_1200x1200_fit_q75_lanczos.jpg 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://www.derekzoladz.com/project/lingo/zoladz-zaveloff_hud7eddf99cc6d96d06786be86b4c3694f_43922_ee210508dc147a9ae58669cff05ddc30.jpg&#34;
               width=&#34;556&#34;
               height=&#34;397&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      Columbus State Librarians selected for ILEAD USA - OHIO 2013
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of the first in-person session in March, teams had only a few hours each evening to create short videos explaining their projects.
[insert initial Lost In Translation video here]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our team was called &amp;lsquo;Lost In Translation&amp;rsquo;, as our original idea for the project was to create a dictionary that would demystify library jargon&amp;hellip; but we ended up designing a classification translation tool.&lt;/p&gt;














&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-designed-by-lost-in-translation-team-member-kirstin-krumsee&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;
        &lt;img alt=&#34;Designed by Lost in Translation team member Kirstin Krumsee&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /project/lingo/lingo-icon_hu207e4e49a229be07996d9569345d69cb_9627_b2643ed9ff14535c8113ce3dc82d417f.png 400w,
               /project/lingo/lingo-icon_hu207e4e49a229be07996d9569345d69cb_9627_74e0182a9380411b61ba499d3fe959a6.png 760w,
               /project/lingo/lingo-icon_hu207e4e49a229be07996d9569345d69cb_9627_1200x1200_fit_lanczos_3.png 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://www.derekzoladz.com/project/lingo/lingo-icon_hu207e4e49a229be07996d9569345d69cb_9627_b2643ed9ff14535c8113ce3dc82d417f.png&#34;
               width=&#34;400&#34;
               height=&#34;289&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      Designed by Lost in Translation team member Kirstin Krumsee
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;














&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-ui-design-mock-up-for-lingo&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;
        &lt;img alt=&#34;UI Design Mock-up for Lingo&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /project/lingo/lingo-1_hue7c37ef7fd82e18ba52bcceb78930e5d_103042_d20273d6555a1df030f7c7bfcbf7c06a.png 400w,
               /project/lingo/lingo-1_hue7c37ef7fd82e18ba52bcceb78930e5d_103042_c0cb79d8bec7995abb7b187fbbadb7cf.png 760w,
               /project/lingo/lingo-1_hue7c37ef7fd82e18ba52bcceb78930e5d_103042_1200x1200_fit_lanczos_3.png 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://www.derekzoladz.com/project/lingo/lingo-1_hue7c37ef7fd82e18ba52bcceb78930e5d_103042_d20273d6555a1df030f7c7bfcbf7c06a.png&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;733&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      UI Design Mock-up for Lingo
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve met some lifelong friends during this year. I&amp;rsquo;m sure we&amp;rsquo;ll meet again on a number of future projects. Project code is available on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dzoladz/know-the-lingo&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;, although unmaintained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We made a final pitch of the application to our local library administrations, participating organizations and partners, as well as to the State Library of Ohio Board.&lt;/p&gt;














&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-describing-lingo-and-its-role&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;
        &lt;img alt=&#34;Describing Lingo and it&amp;#39;s Role&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /project/lingo/board-presentation_hu3d03a01dcc18bc5be0e67db3d8d209a6_279786_042e557b40ad43c26bb3c07cde4c4ffe.jpg 400w,
               /project/lingo/board-presentation_hu3d03a01dcc18bc5be0e67db3d8d209a6_279786_b21d928ac9a867aca3ff66eedd14f4e5.jpg 760w,
               /project/lingo/board-presentation_hu3d03a01dcc18bc5be0e67db3d8d209a6_279786_1200x1200_fit_q75_lanczos.jpg 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://www.derekzoladz.com/project/lingo/board-presentation_hu3d03a01dcc18bc5be0e67db3d8d209a6_279786_042e557b40ad43c26bb3c07cde4c4ffe.jpg&#34;
               width=&#34;666&#34;
               height=&#34;760&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      Describing Lingo and it&amp;rsquo;s Role
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
