<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>TEDSIG on Derek Zoladz</title>
    <link>https://www.derekzoladz.com/tags/tedsig/</link>
    <description>Recent content in TEDSIG on Derek Zoladz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; {year} Derek C. Zoladz</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.derekzoladz.com/tags/tedsig/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Speculative Library Futures</title>
      <link>https://www.derekzoladz.com/project/tedsig_futures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.derekzoladz.com/project/tedsig_futures/</guid>
      <description>Speculative Library Futures | Post-Pandemic Libraries is the culmination of a yearlong exploration of speculative design and libraries by TEDSIG, the Technical, Electronic, and Digital Services Interest Group of the Academic Library Association of Ohio.    Publication: Speculative Library Futures | Post-Pandemic Libraries doi: doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.4606860   Speculative Card Deck by Mackenzie Salisbury and Shannon Marie Robinson integrates Guy Debord&amp;rsquo;s dérive into a beautifully-designed, critical deck of prompts and actions to generate situations that disrupt the traditional use value assigned to the library.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speculative Design &amp; Libraries</title>
      <link>https://www.derekzoladz.com/project/tedsig2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.derekzoladz.com/project/tedsig2020/</guid>
      <description>As Co-Chair of the Technical, Electronic, and Digital Services Interest Group (TEDSIG) - a community within the Academic Library Association of Ohio (ALAO) - my professional experiences have circumvented the shared set of historical struggles that define the group&amp;rsquo;s identity.
TEDSIG was founded in 1993 as the Technical Services Interest Group (TSIG). The interest group’s name and scope was changed in June 2007 to Technical, Electronic, and Digital Services Interest Group (TEDSIG) to better reflect the evolving status of the group’s constituents in traditional and emerging technologies.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>