<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on </title>
    <link>//dzoladz.github.io/website/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; {year} Derek C. Zoladz</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 11:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//dzoladz.github.io/website/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Overview of My Personal Library</title>
      <link>//dzoladz.github.io/website/post/my_library/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//dzoladz.github.io/website/post/my_library/</guid>
      <description>On a day-to-day basis, I work with the Consortium of Ohio Libraries on their open-source ILS Evergreen. Whether it&amp;rsquo;s configuring new circulation policies, adjusting global system settings, or writing SQL to batch update item attributes, I&amp;rsquo;ve explored a significant chunk of Evergreen over the last 3 years. But it&amp;rsquo;s an understatment to say that Evergreen is a massive application. There&amp;rsquo;s still plenty of uncharted functionality.
Evergreen&amp;rsquo;s architecture is designed for multi-tenancy out-of-the-box and built to scale to very large consortia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why ls is exa</title>
      <link>//dzoladz.github.io/website/post/exa/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//dzoladz.github.io/website/post/exa/</guid>
      <description>One of the most common commands that I execute in the terminal is simply to list the contents of a directory. Since I do this so often, being able to quickly and easily digest vast amounts of information about the content of the directory is essential. That&amp;rsquo;s where exa shines.
Out-of-the-box, the default color scheme of exa is finely tuned. I found the intricate use of subtle color distinctions distracting, rather than informative.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Farewell, Nano</title>
      <link>//dzoladz.github.io/website/post/farewell_nano/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//dzoladz.github.io/website/post/farewell_nano/</guid>
      <description>Forever, I&amp;rsquo;ve used nano as my command-line text editor. I&amp;rsquo;ve never had an issue with it. In fact, it&amp;rsquo;s been so reliable that I&amp;rsquo;ve keep it around much longer than I should have. It still works well for most of my needs, but it&amp;rsquo;s time to expand my suite of skills and learn something new.
That&amp;rsquo;s why I&amp;rsquo;m switching to vim.
Out-of-the-box, vim is a tabula rasa, a blank slate, and it feels oddly empty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apps I&#39;m Taking into 2019</title>
      <link>//dzoladz.github.io/website/post/2018apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//dzoladz.github.io/website/post/2018apps/</guid>
      <description>I should probably start off with a bit of a caveat.
Okay. Now that we have that out of the way, here are a few of the apps that I&amp;rsquo;ve discovered over the last 365 days that I&amp;rsquo;ll be taking with me into 2019.
PyCharm
PyCharm is a Python IDE with an extensive collection of plugins. I&amp;rsquo;m using the community edition to develop Python scripts in support the Consortium of Ohio Libraries, mainly to interact with the Evergreen ILS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ohio Digital Network Launches</title>
      <link>//dzoladz.github.io/website/post/dpla/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//dzoladz.github.io/website/post/dpla/</guid>
      <description>Participating in the early group for the technical infrastructure for this project - simply called &amp;lsquo;DPLA Ohio&amp;rsquo; at the time - shaped the trajectory of my career firmly towards technology. Check out the State Library of Ohio&amp;rsquo;s announcement.
And the, visit the Ohio Digital Network!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>