<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Derek Zoladz on Derek Zoladz</title>
    <link>//dzoladz.github.io/website/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Derek Zoladz on Derek Zoladz</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; {year} Derek C. Zoladz</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/website/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Contextualizing EZproxy for Improved Troubleshooting and Problem Reports</title>
      <link>//dzoladz.github.io/website/publication/contextualizing_ezproxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//dzoladz.github.io/website/publication/contextualizing_ezproxy/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speculative Design &amp; Libraries</title>
      <link>//dzoladz.github.io/website/project/tedsig2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//dzoladz.github.io/website/project/tedsig2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As Co-Chair of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.alaoweb.org/igs/tedsig/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Technical, Electronic, and Digital Services Interest Group&lt;/a&gt; (TEDSIG) - a community within the Academic Library Association of Ohio (ALAO) - my professional experiences have circumvented the shared set of historical struggles that define the group&amp;rsquo;s identity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TEDSIG was founded in 1993 as the Technical Services Interest Group (TSIG). The interest group’s name and scope was changed in June 2007 to Technical, Electronic, and Digital Services Interest Group (TEDSIG) to better reflect the evolving status of the group’s constituents in traditional and emerging technologies. By the time that I began working at Columbus State Community College in 2008, it was evidently clear that the traditional role of technical service librarians was on the decline. As a new professional with a bias towards the use of technology in day-to-day library practices, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t understand why - or how -  the technological aspects of the profession were&amp;hellip; &lt;em&gt;on the way out&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the main co-chair responsibilities is to organize an annual event for members of the TEDSIG community. It&amp;rsquo;s an opportunity to contribute to both the growth, and the future direction, of the group. Pondering the overwhelming emptiness of &amp;lsquo;what to do&amp;rsquo; with this tabla rasa, I explored the confusion of my early experiences of technical work in libraries. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t that technological work in libraries was on the way out, it was that &lt;em&gt;a specific way of conducting that technical work was on the way out&lt;/em&gt;. As I&amp;rsquo;m joining the ranks of the mid-career professionals, this gave me pause. As members of Ohio&amp;rsquo;s TEDSIG community, are we actively designing a future for the next generation of library professionals to step into?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To help us explore the design implications of our current and potential library futures, John Jung was invited to speak at TEDSIG 2020.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;john_jung.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;photo of John Jung&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;John Jung is Design Consultant at &lt;a href=&#34;https://johnjung.us/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;johnjung.us&lt;/a&gt; and Programmer/Analyst at The University of Chicago. John is interested in the different ways that research and design might intersect. He has recently spoken on Speculative Design &amp;amp; Strategy at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://johnjung.us/scd_and_strategy.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Symposium on the Future of Libraries&lt;/a&gt; in Seattle, Washington, as well as having lead the provocatively-titled reading group &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.latitudechicago.org/classes-and-workshops/reading-group-design-after-the-end-of-the-world&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Design After the End of the World&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; in his hometown of Chicago. He has a degree in art from Governors State University and a degree in design methods from the IIT Institute of Design.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/nv4Frp8p8fw&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speculative and Critical Design and Libraries&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thomas Moynihan once noted: &amp;ldquo;We perceive the world as anticipations of its future&amp;rdquo;. If nothing else, this statement gives us pause. Just enough of a delay to remove us from immediacy. Allowing us to bring our set of expectations and assumptions to the foreground and reflect upon how these projections of a near-term reality guide our decision-making in the present. As many of our existing library systems are reaching the limits of their effectiveness, the struggle is real. To avoid a future that merely recapitulates - both the positive and negative aspects of - our present solutions, we need to think critically about the design of our future. But maybe more so, we need a toolkit to problematize our present. To shake loose our assumptions, and provide just enough distance to consider alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s where Speculative Design is useful. Where traditional design attempts to solve problems, speculative design attempts to open our minds to new ways of thinking and being. If it is our capacity to envision the future that propels us forward, speculative design has promise as a way to allow us to problematize our present, so as not to repeat our past, by exposing the pre-existing conditions of our current reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>code{4}lib - Pittsburgh, PA</title>
      <link>//dzoladz.github.io/website/post/2020code4lib/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//dzoladz.github.io/website/post/2020code4lib/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;lots-of-firsts-at-code-4-lib-2020&#34;&gt;Lots of Firsts at Code{4}lib 2020&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Code{4}lib is the only major conference that I&amp;rsquo;ve attend with a single track. Most conferences are multi-track. At a multi-track conference, attendees gather for a keynote presentation to kick-off the event. But after that collective experience, everyone develops a self-selected path through simultaneously occurring presentations and activities. At Code{4}lib, all attendees experience the same sequence of sessions, lightning talks, breakouts, and keynotes presentations. There&amp;rsquo;s a definitively stronger sense of community that emerges with a single-track conference. As attendees discuss sessions - through the filters of their own local context and professional focus - a richer understanding of each topic develops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This conference also marks the first time that I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on a committee for a national conference. All of my previous conference planning experiences have been either at the state, regional, or institutional-level. As a member of the Website Working Group for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://2020.code4lib.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;2020 conference&lt;/a&gt;, our team focused mainly on content strategy for web properties and improving the overall experience for on-site and remote attendees, speakers, sponsors, and a host of other interested parties that will stumble upon the content in the coming weeks and months. Our team contributed a number of significant improvements to the overall accessibility of the conference website, including: (1) multiple adjustments to the document structure, (2) removing situations of skipped heading to ease screenreader traversal, and whenever possible (3) swapping static content with variable references, so that next year&amp;rsquo;s working group will be able to customize the conference website more fully by simply updating the content in the site&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code&gt;data.yml&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another first? How about navigating the terrain when your conference coincides with the emergence of the global pandemic: &lt;strong&gt;COVID-19&lt;/strong&gt;. Impossible to anticipate, but major crises highlight the spectrum of financial and logistical realities faced by any organization that hosts a national conference. Hats off to the Local Planning Committee, as they did a spectacular job of keeping on top of CDC recommendations and guiding with definitive leadership. And the Streaming Video Committee, they kept the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLzGHg-1qAr4BxO2TzF9wiFcXVTEn1rRYM&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;remote presentations&lt;/a&gt; connected and engaged with flawless momentum. Bravo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;food-cause-the-answer-is-always-yes&#34;&gt;Food, &amp;lsquo;Cause the Answer is Always &amp;ldquo;Yes&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ❤️ food. One of the things that I savor about visiting another city - for a conference or otherwise - are those brief moments that I actually get to experience it&amp;rsquo;s uniqueness. When I visited Portland, Oregon several years ago, the food culture was truly exceptional. Portland set a rather high bar for my future gastronomic explorations. But, a treasure can be uncovered anywhere. One pleasant surprise along my conference trek has been Minneapolis, Minnesota. Quite literally, the best breakfast tostada I&amp;rsquo;ve ever eaten was at &lt;a href=&#34;https://mercurympls.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Mercury&lt;/a&gt;, which is less than a city block from the light rail station at Nicollet Mall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, Pittsburgh was slightly underwhelming. I did manage to discover a tasty sandwich shop, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eat-gaucho.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Gaucho&amp;rsquo;s Parrilla Argentina &lt;/a&gt; in the Strip District, and the downtown location of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nickysthaikitchen.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Nicky&amp;rsquo;s Thai Kitchen&lt;/a&gt; had a refreshing ginger-infused hot sake that was entirely welcome after a full day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;hotel-oddities&#34;&gt;Hotel Oddities&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A rather large &lt;em&gt;sinkhole&lt;/em&gt; exposed the bowels of the city, and swallowed a city bus in October 2019, remained unrepaired in front of the Westin hotel.
&lt;img src=&#34;https://9b16f79ca967fd0708d1-2713572fef44aa49ec323e813b06d2d9.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/1200x/20191028dsSinkholePATBusLocal03-2-1572277030.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Pittsburgh port authority bus projecting upward from a sinkhole in the middle of a downtown street&#34; title=&#34;Pittsburgh port authority bus projecting upward from a sinkhole in the middle of a downtown street&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the &lt;em&gt;elevator&lt;/em&gt; controls were&amp;hellip; um, peculiar. Rather than attempting to describe it myself, I&amp;rsquo;ll just point to the following 5 minute lightening talk that does a much better job than I can:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/0URpVt0-iVQ?t=9815&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Expectations and Conventions: A code{4}lib Elevator Story&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, it really is a fun &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; informative talk that&amp;rsquo;s worth your next coffee break.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;lots-of-projects-that-i-ll-follow-up-on&#34;&gt;Lots of Projects that I&amp;rsquo;ll Follow-up on:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before heading to the conference, I was already in the process of spinning up the digital asset management system &lt;a href=&#34;https://hyku.samvera.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hyku&lt;/a&gt; on a t3-large EC2 instance. Having just finished writing a &lt;code&gt;docker-compose-ohn.yml&lt;/code&gt; file to set up an instance of Hyku behind the reverse proxy &lt;a href=&#34;https://containo.us/traefik/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Traefik&lt;/a&gt; and using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.portainer.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Portainer&lt;/a&gt; as a container management tool, I was just beginning to explore Hyku&amp;rsquo;s possibilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As such, I stopped by the &lt;a href=&#34;https://samvera.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Samvera&lt;/a&gt; community table during one the breaks for a brief chat about the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hykuforconsortia.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hyku for Consortia&lt;/a&gt; project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//dzoladz.github.io/website/website/post/2020code4lib/hyku_for_consortia.png&#34; alt=&#34;Hexagon-shaped sticker showing Hyku for Consortia logo&#34; title=&#34;Hexagon-shaped sticker showing Hyku for Consortia logo&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;{{&#34; alt=&#34;Hexagon-shaped sticker showing Hyku for Consortia logo&#34; title=&#34;hyku_for_consortia.png&amp;quot; | relURL }} &amp;quot;Hexagon-shaped sticker showing Hyku for Consortia logo&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main focus of the Hyku for Consortia work is to implement a series of changes to the permissions of Hyku. While Hyku is architected as a multi-tenant application right out of the box, there is no current method to provide a group of users with the ability to work across tenants. The Hyku for Consortia project aims to create this feature to facilitate cross-consortial collaborations, as well as allowing the development of administrative governance bodies, say &amp;ldquo;a standards and review body&amp;rdquo;, which could provide guidance and assistance throughout all of the tenants hosted on a single Hyku instance. The project has partnered with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.notch8.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Notch8&lt;/a&gt; out of San Diego to complete the feature development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;just-a-few-others&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip; Just a Few Others&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So many tools, so little time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/httptoolkit&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;HTTP Toolkit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Is this a mashup of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wireshark.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wireshark&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.telerik.com/fiddler&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Fiddler&lt;/a&gt;, but more intuitive? We&amp;rsquo;ll find out soon enough :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mnylc/preservethispodcast&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Preserve this Podcast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Likely of more interest to public libraries, setting up a DIY podcast preservation workshop might appeal to communities with an interest in audio or citizen journalism. Recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve been much more focused on the applicability of &lt;a href=&#34;https://carpentries.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Carpentries&lt;/a&gt; workshops for academic technical services departments&amp;hellip; especially for mid-sized academic libraries located within reasonable geographic proximity to any major metropolitan area. These skills need to be acquired now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wagtail/wagtail&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wagtail&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
It&amp;rsquo;s an open source content management system built on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.djangoproject.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Django&lt;/a&gt;. It can be used to create simple apps that can be embedded into link resolvers, or other library platforms, to allow patrons to report missing PDFs, broken links, or other problematic content within a vendor&amp;rsquo;s platform. Input capture mechanisms can be coded using client-side Javascript.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.browserstack.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;BrowserStack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Execute automated browser tests as part of a CI/CD pipeline. There&amp;rsquo;s a free-tier planning for testing open source projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mherrmann/helium&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Helium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
An alternative to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.selenium.dev/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Selenium&lt;/a&gt; for driving a browser. Useful for application testing and automating routine chores. I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to giving this tool a test drive. The simplified API appears magical.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apps I&#39;m Taking into 2020</title>
      <link>//dzoladz.github.io/website/post/2019apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//dzoladz.github.io/website/post/2019apps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While it&amp;rsquo;s a major challenge to identify all of the scripts, command line tools, and web-based applications that have influenced my thoughts and workflow over the previous year,
here&amp;rsquo;s a set of applications that I&amp;rsquo;m excited to take with me into the new year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/laurent22/joplin&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Joplin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Built upon node.js and electron, Joplin is an open source note taking application. At the moment, I&amp;rsquo;m using it as a well-structured notebook to recall quotes and collect ideas of all sorts. With the ability to sync notebooks to both &lt;a href=&#34;https://owncloud.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;OwnCloud&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://nextcloud.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;NextCloud&lt;/a&gt; - as well as several other storage solutions - the availability of my notebooks across multiple OSes and environments makes it an application that I&amp;rsquo;ll enjoy on many occasions in 2020+.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dockstation.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Dockstation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
If you want: (1) a gentle, graphical, introduction to engineering microservice-based applications with Docker Compose, (2) an interface to the container registry of Docker Hub, and (3) the ability to expose your container logs with the click of a button, DockStation is a wonderful gateway into the world of containers. I develop all of my &lt;code&gt;docker-compose.yml&lt;/code&gt; files using Dockstation on macOS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pi-hole.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Pi-Hole&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Running on a raspberry pi 3 on my home LAN, Pi-Hole provides DNS-level ad blocking on the network. I&amp;rsquo;m using Pi-hole as my DHCP server to assign IP addresses to clients on the LAN.  Via &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.debian.org/dnsmasq&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;dnsmasq&lt;/a&gt;, Pi-hole is also responsible for resolving a few host names on the LAN for applications like my Koha instance and backup server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jekyllrb.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
While working with the Code4Lib web team on the 2020 (Pittsburgh, PA) conference website, I&amp;rsquo;ve become acquainted with this ruby-based static site generator. I&amp;rsquo;ve been using &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; for my personal website, as well as for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://info.cool-cat.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Consortium of Ohio Libraries&lt;/a&gt; website, for roughly 2 years. Hugo has been reliable, but Jekyll as several themes for software project documentation and product marketing that have simple, yet complete, designs. I&amp;rsquo;ll likely explore these themes for other projects in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bitwarden.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Bitwarden&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
As I&amp;rsquo;m currently using LastPass, I&amp;rsquo;ve only begun to evaluate the full potential of BitWarden. I prefer open source applications, but this password management solution falls into the aspirational category for the coming year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;GitLab&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
According to the project website, &amp;ldquo;GitLab is a complete DevOps platform&amp;rdquo;. My main reason for creating a GitLab account is to explore the broader range of open source projects, whose primary source code repository might live within the GitLab ecosystem. As an example, the Evergreen ILS community writes documentation using &lt;a href=&#34;http://asciidoc.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Asciidoc&lt;/a&gt;. Experiments have begun using &lt;a href=&#34;https://antora.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Antora&lt;/a&gt; for generating Evergreen documentation. Antora&amp;rsquo;s source code resides on GitLab.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Curses, It&#39;s Glances</title>
      <link>//dzoladz.github.io/website/post/glances/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//dzoladz.github.io/website/post/glances/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s definitely an argument to be made for using lightweight apps that minimize installed dependencies in an effort to: (1) minimize the surface area for vulnerabilities and attack vectors, and (2) reduce application complexity for  troubleshooting purposes when something inevitably goes wrong. However, there needs to be a balance between security gains and pleasure in using an application, what&amp;rsquo;s the point in installing it in the first place if you aren&amp;rsquo;t going to use it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An application that sits in the sweet spot is &lt;a href=&#34;https://nicolargo.github.io/glances/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Glances&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Glances uses a plugin archiecture. The documentation contains a &lt;a href=&#34;https://glances.readthedocs.io/en/stable/aoa/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;current list of available plugins&lt;/a&gt;. One of the plugins that deserves highlighting is the AMP (Application Monitoring Process) plugin. AMPs are simple regex statements written into the Glances main &lt;code&gt;glances.conf&lt;/code&gt; configuration file that allow the user to monitor any running processes. Glances configuration file is written in the human readable INI format.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;installation&#34;&gt;Installation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On macOS Catalina, I&amp;rsquo;m using Homebrew as my package manager.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;brew install glances
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it. Simple. But if you&amp;rsquo;re like me, you&amp;rsquo;ll want to adjust the default configuration. The glances directory does not exist by default, so you’ll also need to create it by doing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;mkdir /usr/local/etc/glances
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and then,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;cat /usr/local/Cellar/glances/3.1.3/share/doc/glances/glances.conf &amp;gt; /usr/local/etc/glances/glances.conf
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;keybindings-interactive-commands&#34;&gt;Keybindings (Interactive Commands)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A sampling of the in-app toggles that I&amp;rsquo;ve found useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;kbd&gt;Shift&lt;/kbd&gt;+&lt;kbd&gt;D&lt;/kbd&gt; &lt;strong&gt;show/hide Docker module&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;kbd&gt;Shift&lt;/kbd&gt;+&lt;kbd&gt;A&lt;/kbd&gt; &lt;strong&gt;show/hide AMPs module&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;kbd&gt;&amp;#8592;&lt;/kbd&gt;&lt;kbd&gt;&amp;#8594;&lt;/kbd&gt; &lt;strong&gt;move through Tasks menus&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;kbd&gt;h&lt;/kbd&gt; &lt;strong&gt;show Help&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;kbd&gt;n&lt;/kbd&gt; &lt;strong&gt;show/hide Networks module&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;kbd&gt;1&lt;/kbd&gt; &lt;strong&gt;toggle global CPU and per-CPU stats&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;kbd&gt;2&lt;/kbd&gt; &lt;strong&gt;show/hide left sidebar&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;kbd&gt;5&lt;/kbd&gt; &lt;strong&gt;show/hide top menu&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;follow-up&#34;&gt;Follow up&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, &lt;a href=&#34;https://glances.readthedocs.io/en/stable/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ReadTheDocs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Glances provides several export options for statistical data. One option is Elasticsearch. Indexing the usage data from macOS to be visualized in Kibana running on localhost is a likely next step.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overview of My Personal Library</title>
      <link>//dzoladz.github.io/website/post/my_library/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//dzoladz.github.io/website/post/my_library/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On a day-to-day basis, I work with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://info.cool-cat.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Consortium of Ohio Libraries&lt;/a&gt; on their open-source ILS &lt;a href=&#34;https://evergreen-ils.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Evergreen&lt;/a&gt;. Whether it&amp;rsquo;s configuring new circulation policies, adjusting global system settings, or writing SQL to batch update item attributes, I&amp;rsquo;ve explored a significant chunk of Evergreen over the last 3 years. But it&amp;rsquo;s an understatment to say that Evergreen is a massive application. There&amp;rsquo;s still plenty of uncharted functionality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Evergreen&amp;rsquo;s architecture is designed for multi-tenancy out-of-the-box and built to scale to very large consortia. In the United States, it&amp;rsquo;s the platform for a number of large public library consortia. For a personal library, it&amp;rsquo;s overkill. Developing a personal library is also an opportunity to explore the setup and administer another ILS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For these reasons, I chose another well-known open source ILS used most often by stand-alone public libraries as the foundation for my personal library: &lt;a href=&#34;https://koha-community.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Koha&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Goals for the personal library projected included:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Low stakes copy and original MARC cataloging experience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developing data migration skills (e.g. Koha to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.folio.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;FOLIO&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Diversifying my ILS administration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design and build ILS infrastructure and networking from scratch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll be cataloging my personal collection of library-related books on my local network using the following hardware.
&lt;video controls src=&#34;//dzoladz.github.io/website/website/post/my_library/koha_server.mp4&#34;&gt;&lt;/video&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why ls is exa</title>
      <link>//dzoladz.github.io/website/post/exa/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//dzoladz.github.io/website/post/exa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the most common commands that I execute in the terminal is simply to list the contents of a directory. Since I do this so often, being able to quickly and easily digest vast amounts of information about the content of the directory is essential. That&amp;rsquo;s where &lt;a href=&#34;https://the.exa.website/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;exa&lt;/a&gt; shines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Out-of-the-box, the default color scheme of &lt;code&gt;exa&lt;/code&gt; is finely tuned. I found the intricate use of subtle color distinctions distracting, rather than informative. As such, I would need to modify the color definitions to suit my personal goals of: (1) being able to easily differentiate between directory content that my current user owns or is a member of the assigned group, (2) rapidly distinguish between files and directories, and (3) generally list common metadata elements that experiencing has shown to be frequently useful in troubleshooting an issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the moment, here&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;m using:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;# ------------------------------
# exa - Color Scheme Definitions
# ------------------------------

export EXA_COLORS=&amp;quot;\
da=38;5;245:\
di=38;5;14:\
sn=38;5;28:\
sb=38;5;28:\
uu=38;5;40:\
un=38;5;160:\
gu=38;5;40:\
gn=38:5:160:\
bl=38;5;220:\
ur=37:\
uw=37:\
ux=37:\
ue=37:\
gr=37:\
gw=37:\
gx=37:\
tr=37:\
tw=37:\
tx=37:\
su=37:\
sf=37:\
xa=37&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;exa&lt;/code&gt; has a wide range of configurable settings and features. After barely scratching the surface of exa&amp;rsquo;s functionality, I&amp;rsquo;ve configured a tool that lists directory contents in a clear, and highly meaningful way, that fits my workflow. &lt;a href=&#34;https://the.exa.website/features&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;exa&amp;rsquo;s documentation&lt;/a&gt; provides adequate description to customize output to fix various use cases. For example, I&amp;rsquo;m not using any of the git integration, extended attributes, or unix-like tree expansion of the file system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what am I using? Well&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s spelled out in the &lt;code&gt;ls&lt;/code&gt; alias in my &lt;code&gt;.zshrc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;alias ls=&amp;quot;exa --long --header --links  --inode --blocks --accessed --modified --created --group --all --sort=.name  --group-directories-first&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Farewell, Nano</title>
      <link>//dzoladz.github.io/website/post/farewell_nano/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//dzoladz.github.io/website/post/farewell_nano/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Forever, I&amp;rsquo;ve used &lt;code&gt;nano&lt;/code&gt; as my command-line text editor. I&amp;rsquo;ve never had an issue with it. In fact, it&amp;rsquo;s been so reliable that I&amp;rsquo;ve keep it around much longer than I should have. It still works well for most of my needs, but it&amp;rsquo;s time to expand my suite of skills and learn something new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s why I&amp;rsquo;m switching to &lt;code&gt;vim&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Out-of-the-box, &lt;code&gt;vim&lt;/code&gt; is a &lt;em&gt;tabula rasa&lt;/em&gt;, a blank slate, and it feels oddly empty. To fill this vacuum, my first step in making the transition was to explore plugin managers. Of course, this is following an introductory period to learn the basics. If I was going to successfully make the switch, I was going to need to first personalize my instance &lt;code&gt;vim&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I selected Tim Pope&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tpope/vim-pathogen&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;pathogen.vim&lt;/a&gt; as my plugin manager. &lt;code&gt;pathogen.vim&lt;/code&gt; allows for each plugin to be placed into its own version-controlled directory and loaded at runtime. Installing a plugin is straightforward: &lt;code&gt;git clone&lt;/code&gt; into &lt;code&gt;~/.vim/bundle/&lt;/code&gt;. Simple, maintainable, elegant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a few of the plugins that comprise my base:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/nanotech/jellybeans.vim&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;jellybeans.vim&lt;/a&gt;: Because everyone needs a cheerful, dark-mode enabled, color scheme.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/scrooloose/nerdtree&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;nerdtree.vim&lt;/a&gt;: If you&amp;rsquo;re going to be using &lt;code&gt;vim&lt;/code&gt; for any amount of time, you&amp;rsquo;ll want to have a file explorer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tpope/vim-fugitive&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;fugitive.vim&lt;/a&gt;: A way more advanced git wrapper than I currently need, but a rich avenue for exploration and growth. I&amp;rsquo;m basically using this plugin to display git information in the &lt;code&gt;&#39;statusline&#39;&lt;/code&gt; via&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/itchyny/lightline.vim&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;lightline.vim&lt;/a&gt;: In a nutshell, an easy to use and highly configurable &lt;code&gt;&#39;statusline&#39;&lt;/code&gt; plugin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to take &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dzoladz/.vim&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;my initial configuration&lt;/a&gt; for a spin!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apps I&#39;m Taking into 2019</title>
      <link>//dzoladz.github.io/website/post/2018apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//dzoladz.github.io/website/post/2018apps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I should probably start off with a bit of a caveat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/TTRyEOT.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image of Steve Jobs calling all categories of computer program an app.&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay. Now that we have that out of the way, here are a few of the apps that I&amp;rsquo;ve discovered over the last 365 days that I&amp;rsquo;ll be taking with me into 2019.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jetbrains.com/pycharm/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;PyCharm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
PyCharm is a Python IDE with an extensive collection of plugins. I&amp;rsquo;m using the community edition to develop Python scripts in support the Consortium of Ohio Libraries, mainly to interact with the Evergreen ILS. PyCharm includes a useful testing suite and refactoring tools, while also providing straightforward integration with GitHub and seamless implementation of pipenv virtual environments. Simple on-boarding for new python developers, but feature rich and extensible as your needs grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.iterm2.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;iTerm2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Essentially, a terminal replacement for the native terminal application that shipped with my MacBook Pro. I find the ability to split terminal panes both vertically and horizontally an advantage for different tasks. I&amp;rsquo;ve also made use of the integrated search feature quite a bit. With colorized output, it&amp;rsquo;s beautiful to use. There are also a slew of other powerful features that I rarely make use of (in 2018, at least).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sequelpro.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Sequel Pro&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
A MacOS native application for interacting with MySQL and MariaDB and a replacement phpMyAdmin. Enough said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sqlitebrowser/sqlitebrowser&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;DB browser for SQLite&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Open source application to create and edit SQLite database files. My main use case is to import Excel worksheets and be able to execute SQL commands on the data. Maybe more importantly is the ability to import multiple Excel worksheets, join them together, and query across them. This tool said me quite a bit of time when working with the Academic Library Association of Ohio (ALAO) this past year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://brave.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Brave&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
A web browser built on Chromium and the Blink rendering engine, a fork of WebKit. It&amp;rsquo;s my drop-in replacement for Google Chrome at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/robbyrussell/oh-my-zsh&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Oh My Zsh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;ve abandoned Bash and began using the Z shell on my MacBook Pro. I&amp;rsquo;m a very big fan of the available themes, which have assisted with git workflow and generally made working in the terminal a much more pleasant and enjoyable experience. Highly recommended.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/berick/pysip2&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;PySip2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
A Python-based SIP 2 client that has been invaluable this year. I&amp;rsquo;ve used this tool for testing SIP connectivity during the statewide implementation of Lynda.com, while establishing authentication for the Ohio Digital Library, for new subscriptions to Hoopla, and also while implementing a PC management system at one on the COOL libraries. Outstanding little application.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ohio Digital Network Launches</title>
      <link>//dzoladz.github.io/website/post/dpla/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//dzoladz.github.io/website/post/dpla/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Participating in the early group for the technical infrastructure for this project - simply called &amp;lsquo;DPLA Ohio&amp;rsquo; at the time - shaped the trajectory of my career firmly towards technology. Check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://library.ohio.gov/news/ohio-digital-network-collections-debuts-dpla/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;State Library of Ohio&amp;rsquo;s announcement&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the, visit the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ohiodigitalnetwork.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ohio Digital Network&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beam Me Up, Scotty: Migrating into an Evergreen Consortium</title>
      <link>//dzoladz.github.io/website/publication/rightclick2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//dzoladz.github.io/website/publication/rightclick2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Augmented Reality at Columbus State Library [Photo Essay]</title>
      <link>//dzoladz.github.io/website/project/thurgood/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//dzoladz.github.io/website/project/thurgood/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thurgood Marshall and the Supreme Court&lt;/em&gt; was an interactive exhibit at the Columbus State Library in 2015. Posters were brought to life using the augmented reality app &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.aurasma.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Aurasma&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Using emerging technology, team members created the exhibit and online guide that was enjoyed and appreciated by the community, ranging from 5th graders to local business leaders. With the help of many collaborators, the team went beyond the exhibit to create a wide range of programs including a film series, an art exhibit, a lecture series, and a companion display and programming in the Bookstore. This innovative and extraordinary program of exhibits and events provided the campus and community with the opportunity to learn more deeply about events and individuals that have had an impact on the way we live today.&amp;rdquo; - &lt;strong&gt;CSCC Quality Team Award, Gold 2016&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;




&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;exhibit-poster.png&#34; /&gt;



&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; &gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;Announcement board for the exhibit&lt;/h4&gt;
  
&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;




&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;thurgood-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Post-Award Photo of the Major Library Staff Contributors to the Project.&#34; /&gt;



&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; &gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;(from left to right) Frank Neutzling, Daryl Brown, Derek Zoladz&lt;/h4&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Post-Award Photo of the Major Library Staff Contributors to the Project.
    
    
    
  &lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;




&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;thurgood-2.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; &gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;View of Exhibit from Main Entrance&lt;/h4&gt;
  
&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;




&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;thurgood-3.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; &gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;Display at Columbus State Bookstore&lt;/h4&gt;
  
&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s an example of a triggered augmented reality layer for one of the case posters. There is no audio on this clip.

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/hJRJTxkP7tY&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Know the Lingo: How ILEAD Ohio Influenced Library Collaboration and Discovery for Patrons</title>
      <link>//dzoladz.github.io/website/publication/know-the-lingo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//dzoladz.github.io/website/publication/know-the-lingo/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lingo</title>
      <link>//dzoladz.github.io/website/project/lingo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//dzoladz.github.io/website/project/lingo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ohio’s first ILEAD USA was a multi-state immersive continuing education program that develops library leaders through projects based on community needs via the application of participatory technology tools. Ohio participants joined others from Colorado, Illinois, Iowa, and Utah in this national initiative. ILEAD USA was funded by a Laura Bush 21st Century Librarian Program grant to the State Library of Illinois from the Institute of Museum and Library Services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Myself, and a former CSCC colleague Julie Zaveloff, were selected as part of the initial group from Ohio. Our team was rounded out by other librarians from around the state:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kirstin Krumsee, State Library of Ohio&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jessica Crossfield McIntosh, Otterbein University&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;David Green, OhioNET&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;




&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;zoladz-zaveloff.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Columbus State Librarians selected for ILEAD USA - OHIO 2013&#34; /&gt;



&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; &gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;Derek Zoladz and Julie Zaveloff&lt;/h4&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Columbus State Librarians selected for ILEAD USA - OHIO 2013
    
    
    
  &lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of the first in-person session in March, teams had only a few hours each evening to create short videos explaining their projects.
[insert initial Lost In Translation video here]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our team was called &amp;lsquo;Lost In Translation&amp;rsquo;, as our original idea for the project was to create a dictionary that would demystify library jargon&amp;hellip; but we ended up designing a classification translation tool.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;lingo-icon.png&#34; alt=&#34;Designed by Lost in Translation team member Kirstin Krumsee&#34; /&gt;



&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; &gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;Application Logo&lt;/h4&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Designed by Lost in Translation team member Kirstin Krumsee
    
    
    
  &lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;




&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;lingo-1.png&#34; /&gt;



&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; &gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;UI Design Mock-up for Lingo&lt;/h4&gt;
  
&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve met some lifelong friends during this year. I&amp;rsquo;m sure we&amp;rsquo;ll meet again on a number of future projects. Project code is available on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dzoladz/know-the-lingo&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;, although unmaintained.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We made a final pitch of the application to our local library administrations, participating organizations and partners, as well as to the State Library of Ohio Board.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;board-presentation.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Describing Lingo and it&amp;#39;s Role&#34; /&gt;



&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; &gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;Derek Zoladz and Kirstin Krumsee&lt;/h4&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Describing Lingo and it&amp;rsquo;s Role
    
    
    
  &lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
